Guide to the International Syndicate Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
International Syndicate records
1904-1963
GEN MSS 1425
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
144.42
(119 boxes)
The International Syndicate records, which span from 1904 to 1963, contain business records, artwork, printing plates, and other papers by or related to the business dealings of the International Syndicate. The records document the company's output, along with business dealings between newspapers, independent contractors, and International Syndicate. Artwork and printing mats make up the largest portion of the collection and are primarily comprised of crossword puzzles and children's page elements.
International Syndicate
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 98-108, 120-143: Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Rulon-Miller Books on the Jockey Hollow Fund, 2017.
Arrangement
Organized into six series: I. Artwork, 1904-1955. II. Children's page materials, 1910-1961. III. Crossword puzzles, 1910-1962. IV. Metal printing plates, 1914-1942. V. Business records, 1904-1963. VI. Scrapbooks, 1904-1941.
International Syndicate
International Syndicate was a Baltimore-based publishing concern that operated from 1910-1961. The company produced feature materials for newspapers, including crossword puzzles and content for children's pages.
Scope and Contents
The International Syndicate records, which span from 1904 to 1963, contain business records, artwork, printing plates, and other papers by or related to the business dealings of the International Syndicate. The records document the company's output, along with business dealings between newspapers, independent contractors, and International Syndicate. Artwork and printing mats make up the largest portion of the collection and are primarily comprised of crossword puzzles and children's page elements.
Publishers and publishing -- Maryland; Newspapers -- United States; Newspaper publishing -- United States; Crossword puzzles -- United States; Children's literature -- United States; Children's periodicals -- United States; Printing plates; Drawings (visual works); International Syndicate
- Artwork, 1904-1955; Series I; 60; (44 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Materials within this series maintain the original physical organization found at time of acquisition with the exception of some oversized materials.
  Scope and Contents
  Contains original and reproduced artwork, including drawings and puzzles, used in the production of International Syndicate content.
  - Drawings, circa 1922 (Box 1)
  - Drawings, circa 1910-1930 (Box 2)
  - Drawings, circa 1908 (Box 3)
  - Drawings, 1911-1933 (Box 4)
  - Drawings, 1911-1933 (Box 5)
  - Drawings, 1908-1928 (Box 6)
  - Drawings, 1908-1928 (Box 6)
  - Drawings, 1920-1923 (Box 7)
  - Drawings, 1924-1927 (Box 8)
  - Drawings, 1936-1942 (Box 9)
  - Drawings, 1909-1924 (Box 10)
  - Drawings, 1909-1910 (Box 11)
  - Drawings, 1934-1939 (Box 12)
  - Drawings, 1935-1937 (Box 13)
  - Drawings, circa 1914 (Box 14)
  - Drawings, undated (Box 15)
  - Drawings, undated (Box 16)
  - Drawings and puzzles, circa 1912 (Box 17)
  - Drawings and puzzles, circa 1924 (Box 18)
  - Drawings and puzzles, circa 1909 (Box 19)
  - Drawings and puzzles, circa 1930 (Box 20)
  - Drawings and puzzles, 1911-1926 (Box 21)
  - Drawings and puzzles, 1910-1939 (Box 22)
  - Drawings and puzzles, 1906-1940 (Box 23)
  - Drawings and puzzles, 1908-1935 (Box 24)
  - Drawings and puzzles, 1920-1933 (Box 25)
  - Drawings and puzzles, undated (Box 26)
  - Drawings and puzzles, 1913-1930 (Box 27)
  - Children's puzzles and games, 1909-1949 (Box 28)
  - Children's puzzles and games, circa 1920-1926 (Box 29)
  - Children's puzzles and games, circa 1923-1955 (Box 30)
  - Drawings and artwork for children's pages, circa 1914-1923 (Box 31)
  - Drawings and artwork for children's pages, 1909-1937 (Box 32)
  - Drawings and artwork for children's pages, 1912-1938 (Box 33)
  - Artwork, 1927-1942 (Box 34)
  - Artwork, 1928-1939 (Box 35)
  - Artwork, 1936 (Box 36)
  - Artwork, 1942-1955 (Box 37)
  - Artwork, 1904-1914 (Box 38)
  - Artwork, undated (Box 39)
  - Artwork, undated (Box 40)
  - Picture reference file, circa 1913-1929 (Box 41)
  - Picture reference file, 1926 (Box 42)
  - Copy cuts, original drawings, and proofs, undated (Box 43)
  - Copy cuts, original drawings, and proofs, undated (Box 44)
- Children's page materials, 1910-1962; Series II; 30.67; (26 boxes)
  Contains drawings, puzzles, and typescripts used in the production of International Syndicate "Children's Page" printing plates and mats. Also contains printed page proofs of completed "Children's Page" layouts.
  - Junior puzzle folders, 1926-1927 (Box 45)
  - Junior puzzle folders, 1928-1930 (Box 46)
  - Junior puzzle folders, 1931-1935 (Box 47)
  - Junior puzzle folders, 1936-1939 (Box 48)
  - Junior puzzle folders, 1939-1941 (Box 49)
  - Dot puzzles--original drawings #1-1320, 1926-1933 (Box 50)
  - Dot puzzles--original drawings #1321-2039, undated (Box 51)
  - Dot puzzles, 1938-1943 (Box 52)
  - Junior puzzle folders, 1934-1943 (Box 53)
  - Junior puzzle folders and dot puzzles, 1928-1942 (Box 54)
  - Puzzles, 1922 (Box 55)
  - Junior puzzles, 1955-1962 (Box 56)
  - Dot puzzles, 1926-1945 (Box 57)
  - Weekly children's page proofs, 1910-1916 (Box 58)
  - Weekly children's page proofs, 1916-1918 (Box 59)
  - Weekly children's page proofs, 1920-1923 (Box 60)
  - Weekly children's page proofs, 1923-1943 (Box 61)
  - Weekly children's page proofs, 1925-1933 (Box 62)
  - Weekly children's page proofs, 1933-1936 (Box 63)
  - Weekly children's page proofs, 1937-1941 (Box 64)
  - Weekly children's page proofs, 1942 (Box 65)
  - Children's daily crossword, 1910-1917 (Box 66)
  - Children's daily crossword, 1911-1920 (Box 67)
  - Children's daily crossword, 1925 (Box 68)
  - Typescripts, 1955-1961 (Box 69)
  - Children's puzzles, 1920-1925 (Box 70)
- Crossword puzzles, 1919-1962; Series III; 28.58; (27 boxes)
  Contains printing mats and plates for crossword puzzles and solutions, original crossword puzzle designs and templates, and printed crossword puzzle proofs.
  - Puzzles, 1925-1928 (Box 71)
  - Puzzles, 1928-1938 (Box 72)
  - Puzzles, 1938-1941 (Box 73)
  - Puzzles and ephemera, 1941-1942 (Box 74)
  - Puzzle pages, 1919-1926 (Box 75)
  - Crossword puzzle solutions, 1946-1953 (Box 76)
  - Crossword puzzle solutions, 1946-1956 (Box 77)
  - Crossword puzzles and mats, 1925-1926 (Box 78)
  - Crossword puzzles and mats, 1926-1936 (Box 79)
  - Crossword puzzles and mats, 1936-1940 (Box 80)
  - Crossword puzzles, mats, and solutions, 1943-1944 (Box 81)
  - Crossword puzzles, mats, and solutions, 1944-1945 (Box 82)
  - Crossword puzzles, mats, and solutions, 1945-1946 (Box 83)
  - Crossword puzzles and mats, 1941-1950 (Box 84)
  - Paper mats and printing plates, circa 1935-1962 (Box 85)
  - Crossword templates, 1923-1934 (Box 86)
  - Crossword templates, 1924-1935 (Box 87)
  - Crossword templates, 1925-1932 (Box 88)
  - Crossword templates, 1926-1939 (Box 89)
  - Crossword templates, 1927-1940 (Box 90)
  - Crossword templates, 1928-1940 (Box 91)
  - Crossword templates, 1928-1940 (Box 92)
  - Crossword templates, 1929-1942 (Box 93)
  - Crossword templates, 1931-1932 (Box 94)
  - Crossword templates, 1931-1936 (Box 95)
  - Crossword templates, 1936-1939 (Box 96)
  - Crossword templates, 1941-1942 (Box 97)
- Printing plates, 1914-1956; Series IV; 11.92; (11 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 100-110: Materials restricted due to weight and fragility. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Materials within this series maintain the original physical organization found at time of acquisition.
  Contains metal printing plates for children's page elements produced by International Syndicate.
  - Children's page cuts, 1914-1931 (Box 98)
  - Children's page cuts, 1917-1930 (Box 99)
  - Children's page cuts, 1921-1932 (Box 100)
  - Children's page cuts, 1928-1933 (Box 101)
  - Children's page cuts, 1919-1939 (Box 102)
  - Plates, 1914-1929 (Box 103)
  - Plates, 1914-1940 (Box 104)
  - Plates, 1914-1942 (Box 105)
  - Plates, 1928-1940 (Box 106)
  - Plates, 1941-1942 (Box 107)
  - Plates, 1956 (Box 108)
- Business records, 1904-1963; Series V; 13.25; (11 boxes)
  Materials within this series are organized by content type, then chronologically within that grouping.
  Contains documentation related to the business dealings of International Syndicate including ledgers, correspondence, and printing samples.
  - Ledgers, 1904-1962 (Box 109)
  - Ledgers, 1914-1959 (Box 110)
  - Ledgers, 1918-1955 (Box 111)
  - Ledgers, 1926-1963 (Box 112)
  - Ledger, 1928-1952 (Box 113)
  - Ledger and business papers, 1945-1961 (Box 114)
  - Ledger, 1960-1963 (Box 115)
  - Business papers, correspondence, and proofs, 1904-1962 (Box 116)
  - Business papers, correspondence, and proofs, 1919-1963 (Box 117)
  - Business papers, correspondence, and proofs, 1925-1948 (Box 118)
  - Business papers, correspondence, and proofs, 1929-1962 (Box 119)
- Scrapbooks, 1904-1941; Series VI
  Boxes 122-145: Restricted fragile material. Materials are currently in process; access to unprocessed materials may be limited. Contact Access Services for further information.
  Materials within this series are arranged chronologically.
  Scrapbooks contain print samples and page proofs of puzzles and articles created by artists and writers working for International Syndicate.
  - Scrapbook, 1904-1905 (Box 120 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1906-1907 (Box 121 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1907-1908 (Box 122 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1908 (Box 123 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1908-1909 (Box 124 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1909 (Box 125 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1909-1910 (Box 126 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1911 (Box 127 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1911-1912 (Box 128 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1912-1913 (Box 129 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1912-1914 (Box 130 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1914 (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1917-1918 (Box 132 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1922-1923 (Box 133 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1923-1932 (Box 134 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1927-1928 (Box 135 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, circa 1928-1930 (Box 136 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1930-1932 (Box 137 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1933-1935 (Box 138 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1935-1938 (Box 139 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook, 1938-1941 (Box 140 (Oversize))